<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Methods on Zonge</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/ZongeWebDev/methods/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Methods on Zonge</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/ZongeWebDev/methods/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title># UAV (Drone) Magnetic Survey (nT)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ZongeWebDev/methods/airbonemethods/airbone_magnetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ZongeWebDev/methods/airbonemethods/airbone_magnetics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;method&#34;&gt;Method&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Total magnetic intensity varies laterally in proportion to the amount of magnetic minerals present. It can be useful to find both magnetic highs and magnetic lows depending on the application and target type.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Measurements are made along lines using a total-field magnetometer suspended from an Unmanned Aerial Vehicle (Drone). It is necessary to perform calibration flights for compensation and perform diurnal corrections on the dataset using a magnetic base station. All pilots are FAA part 107 certified and operations are carried out in compliance with Zonge’s UAV SMS program.&#xA;Drone magnetics strikes a balance between helicopter borne surveys and ground surveys. There may be a bit less detail than ground surveys but the draping using an RTK based drone is generally better and so there can be more detail than helicopter surveys. Helicopter surveys are generally the most cost-efficient option for large areas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controled-Source AMT (CSAMT)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ZongeWebDev/methods/groundmethods/csamt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ZongeWebDev/methods/groundmethods/csamt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;method-ohmm&#34;&gt;Method (ohm·m)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CSAMT surveys are utilized to measure the calculated resistivity structure of the Earth. A transmitter dipole is deployed at a large distance away from the receiver grid, transmitting a controlled electrical signal over a range of frequencies. The orthogonal components of the electric and magnetic fields are measured at the receiver with grounded dipoles and a magnetic antenna. The resistivity values relate to the geological response of the ground, providing information on resistivity contrasts of more or less resistive rock packages or structures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gravity (mGal)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ZongeWebDev/methods/groundmethods/gravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ZongeWebDev/methods/groundmethods/gravity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;method&#34;&gt;Method&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A gravity survey consists of taking measurements of Earth’s gravitational field, which varies based on the density of the material below each measurement point on the surface. As the density of the material increases, so does the acceleration due to gravity at that location. Zonge produces the Complete Bouger Anomaly value for each station. A gravity survey may be designed as a grid, profiles, or sparsely populated stations across an area of interest using 1-2 people, a gravimeter, and a base station.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Induced Polarization (IP)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ZongeWebDev/methods/groundmethods/ip/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ZongeWebDev/methods/groundmethods/ip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;method&#34;&gt;Method&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An IP survey is produced by injecting current into the ground and measuring the change in voltage with respect to time (TD) or a lag in phase between the receiver and transmitter waveforms (CR). The voltage potential is measured between two receiver electrodes, and as the spacing between transmitter electrodes and the receiver pairs increases, the depth of investigation increases.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In simple terms, the target’s ability to store electrical energy after the current is turned off or after the polarity switches indicates the material is chargeable (ie sulfides, graphite, clays, or other alteration products).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnetotellurics (MT/AMT)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ZongeWebDev/methods/groundmethods/mt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ZongeWebDev/methods/groundmethods/mt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;method-ohmm&#34;&gt;Method (ohm·m)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The magnetotelluric (MT) method is a passive imaging technique that utilizes naturally occurring electromagnetic fields to examine subsurface structures to depths of up to 10’s of kilometers. This is the deepest sounding electromagnetic exploration method.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The signal source comes from global-scale lightning discharges and solar wind, and the resolution is governed by subsurface resistivity contrasts as a function of frequency. Using grounded dipoles and sensitive magnetic field antennas, the electrical and magnetic fields are measured over a suite of frequencies (0.001-1,000Hz) and produce apparent resistivity measurements (&lt;em&gt;ohm*m&lt;/em&gt;) that represent the geologic structures at depth. Each station is occupied for multiple hours, often overnight.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TEM (ohm·m)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ZongeWebDev/methods/groundmethods/tem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ZongeWebDev/methods/groundmethods/tem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;transient-electromagnetic-time-domain-em-and-nanotem&#34;&gt;Transient Electromagnetic (Time-domain EM) and NanoTEM&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A TEM survey involves generating an electromagnetic field by transmitting a time-varying current into a transmitter loop. A magnetic antenna measures the response of the secondary magnetic field induced by eddy currents to obtain information on the resistivity (ohm·m) of the subsurface. Conductors are ideal targets because they will produce measurable b-field responses with respect to time after transmitter turn off.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We observe the induced voltages from the secondary field at the receiver, where each decay waveform is measured in discrete time intervals, or time gates, that vary from microseconds (NanoTEM) to milliseconds. A slow rate of decay after the transmitter turn-off indicates a more conductive subsurface, where a quick decay indicates resistive material.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
